Contact

7415602179 (Mobile) saurabhnemabhopal@outlook.c om

www.linkedin.com/in/ saurabhnema27 (LinkedIn) saurabhnema27.github.io (Personal)

Top Skills

Python

PHP

MySQL

Languages

Hindi

English

Certifications

CutShort Certified Laravel - Basic

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)

CutShort Certified PHP - Basic

Introduction to HTML5

python django

Honors-Awards

Doer and Alone Sailor

Appreciation for maintaining the SLA

Saurabh Nema

PHP Developer at e-Zest Solutions
Pune

Summary

+3 yrs of development experience in RestAPI's, worked on technologies like PHP(7.x), Python(2.5x), MySQL(5.6) and Java(8.x) with Frameworks like Laravel(5.8x), Django(2.2x), Springboot(2.1.2x), magneto(2.x with database), with this a sounding knowledge on Git, Docker, AWS and python libs.

Experience

e-Zest Solutions

1 year 2 months

PHP Developer

March 2021 - Present (11 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

working on SLA and Incident tickets for operational work.

Taking the small case Diets tickets for improving the system workflow.

Majorly working on magenta DB stack to optimise the system flow and optimisation of workflow.

Majorly works on tickets which is based on DIET, RCA, SDMR work.

Jr PHP Developer

December 2020 - February 2021 (3 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Working on Magento 2x,

working on automation scripts,

Working on the data migration process.

MAVEN CLUSTER ™

Laravel Developer

June 2020 - December 2020 (7 months)

Indore, Madhya Pradesh, India

Worked on the various Projects which is made on Restful Services which I'm making on PHP 7.2x and Laravel 5.7x MVC based web application.

Projects were:

1. NoShaadi: It's a dating app which has a distance logic, profile s1een logics, data-driven logics and all are made on laravel.

2. Fitness App: This is related to fitness track your needs and daily-to-day activities, Feed section where other people can see you feeds, nearby Gyms and much more.

3. OurJobFlow: This is a Job portal where a jobseeker come and search for a job and apply for a job.

4. AppsBuilder: This is a project which gives you details of your dream project and MVP of it.

apart from this, I've also used the middleware for the login user to get features and URL throttle.

Using Git Version controlling for the codebase.

Worked with the 3rd party API for Authorization of user for Login / Registration like (Facebook and Google).

BrandzGarage Laravel Developer January 2020 - May 2020 (5 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Lov.Cash
Back End Developer
December 2018 - December 2019 (1 year 1 month)
Bengaluru Area, India

Worked on Restful API on Tech Stack J2EE, Spring-Boot, Maven, JPA.

Managed the AWS Infra and Tools like VPC, Security Groups, Internet Gateway, Subnet, Elastic IP, RDS, IAM User Policy, EC2 Instances.

Made a Speech Recognition System for daily meetings which convert the daily scrum to TXT format and mail to everyone on Python 3.6x used Speech recognization lib, Mail, SMTP protocol, File handling,

Made a project on Django for User Post Implementation used an ORM and Mapping relationships with DB and worked on Multiple Database to store the information, used the forms and authentication user model for Meta class.

Created a Website Using the Laravel MVC Framework and used the Templating concept, dynamic binding data.

Made the Documents of Work Loads and Followed the best practices to make it avil for all Domains.

Bitfumes Webnologies software developer January 2018 - December 2018 (1 year) Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh, India

Worked as a software developer trainee and role to solve the complex logical problems based on web apps made RestApi's for universal access of the product across the globe.

Made a Powerfull RESTAPI's which is in the market for Financial use, the whole logic of API's is made on Laravel MVC and the security on the server side is been made from scratch using middleware, CORS, Throttle, URL checking, Token Generation, Using the Auth Module, Passport, CORS Platforms.

Get my hands dirty on Python 3.4x libs like speech recognition, requests, bs4, oops, email, win32.com, pandas, mathplotlib.

Education

Rajiv Gandhi Prodyogiki Vishwavidyalaya Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science · (2013 - 2017)

Central Board of Secondary Education High School, PCM + I.P. · (2012 - 2013)

Central Board of Secondary Education

High School · (2011 - 2012)